CURRICULUM VITAE

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Name: - Surajit Roy

Email:- surajitroy9064@gmail.com

Current Address: Chennai, Tamil Nadu, 603103 Permanent Address: Purulia, West Bengal, 723201

Contact no:- +91 9064516911



CAREER OBJECTIVE

An Enthusiastic Software Engineer who is willing to learn new technologies, take up interesting challenges, and contribute to the team's success through sheer hardwork and dedication. Possess technical and functional knowledge of the system with 1 year of experience. Highly Motivated to work and be part of an organisation that like talented minds.

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION

Qualification	Board/University	Year of passing	<u>Percentage</u>
Master of Computer Applications	KIIT UNIVERSITY	2021-2023	8.26 CGPA
Bachelor of Computer Applications	Bengal Institute Of Science & Technology	2018-2021	8.83 CGPA
12th	WBCHSE	2018	61.00%
10th	WBBSE	2016	69.57%

WORK EXPERIENCE

Organization	Designation	From	To
Financial Software & Systems (P) Limited (FSS)	Intern	Feb. 2023	Jul. 2023
Financial Software & Systems (P) Limited (FSS)	Software Engineer	Aug. 2023	Present

Roles & Responsibilities

Intern in Financial Software & Systems (P) Limited, Chennai from Feb.2023-Jul.2023

- Worked with developers to identify and remove software bugs.
- Analyzed source code to identify functionality issues.
- Coordinate with team members in developing product.

Software Engineer in Financial Software & Systems (P) Limited, Chennai from Aug.2023-Present

- Develops and maintains applications and databases by evaluating client needs.
- In Android, I collaborated with software development and testing team members to design and develop robust solutions, meeting client requirements for functionality, scalability, and performance.

- Developed robust, scalable, modular and API-centric infrastructures. Designing and developing apps for the Android ecosystem.
- Implementing RESTful API services for creating, retrieving, updating and deleting data usually in JSON.
- Building user interface, data visualizations and designed overall user experience.

Technical Skills

Technologies	Android, Flutter, Core Java, Kotlin, Html, CSS, Javascript

Tools	Android Studio, Github, Bitbucket, VS Code,
Databases	MySQL, SQLite, Postgres

Project Experience:

Project #1 : API creation for Android

Company : Financial Software & Systems, Chennai

Technologies: Core Java, Kotlin, Android, SQLite

Client : Al-Rajhi Bank

Description: Following the client's specifications. In this project, I utilized the Volley library and employed SQLite database as per the client's requirements. The objective was to seamlessly integrate API creation into the Android platform, ensuring efficient communication between the app and server. By adhering to the client's instructions, I successfully implemented the necessary functionalities.

LINGUISTIC ABILITY

- 1. English
- 2. Hindi
- 3. Bengali

PERSONAL SKILLS

- 1. Team Player
- 2. Discipline
- 3. Fast Learner

INTERESTS

- 1. Traveling
- 2. Cricket, Football